Guide to the William L. Mertz transportation collection, 1955-1990
George Mason University Libraries
Special Collections and Archives, George Mason University
William L. Mertz transportation collection
1955-1990
George Mason University. Special Collections and Archives.
Lee Mertz, 1920-1993
C0050
47.5 linear feet (60 boxes)
The collection contains transportation related materials collected over a 45-year period. Types of materials include scholarly journal articles dealing with transportation topics, summaries of congressional acts relating to transportation, official reports and studies of transportation agencies, summaries of speeches given by transportation officials, and personal correspondence among transportation officials.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Collection donated by Jonathan Gifford, Marty L. Freeman, and Perry M. Kent in 1994-2000.
Biographical Information
William Lee Mertz, a former Federal Highway Administration Associate Administrator, played a leading role in planning and developing the Interstate system of highways in the United States. Born in 1920, Mertz started his career as a highway engineer with the Bureau of Public Roads in the Department of Commerce. As a field engineer, Mertz worked on many interesting and important transportation projects. He took part in the 1955 Road Test in Ottawa, Illinois, where the basic designs for Interstate pavements were developed. Mertz was assigned in 1956 to the Bureau of Standards to develop standards for computer software for use in highway engineering applications. During the 1960s he worked with such groups as the National Capital Transit Agency in Washington, D.C. and the Tri-State Transportation Commission in New York. He also served as an administrator in the planning of the Interstate Highway System, including the Washington Beltway, I-95 in Maryland, and the Washington Metrorail System. In 1969 Mertz returned to the Federal Highway Administration as Chief of the Urban Planning Division and developed transportation planning studies in all 213 metropolitan areas of the nation. After he left the Federal Highway Administration, Mertz took it upon himself to assemble documents and materials that were important in the development of the Interstate system, and, more generally, to the development of highways and urban transportation policy. Mertz died in 1993.
Scope and Content
The collection contains transportation related materials collected over a 45 year period. Types of materials include scholarly journal articles dealing with transportation topics, summaries of congressional acts relating to transportation, official reports and studies of transportation agencies, summaries of speeches given by transportation officials, and personal correspondence among transportation officials. The material covers a wide variety of topics, such as The Federal Highway Acts, bridges, buses, the environment, transportation in cities, commuting, and trucking. Organizations represented by materials in the collection include the Federal Highway Administration,the Department of Transportation, the Tri-State Transportation Commission, and the American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged alphabetically by subject.
Adjunct Descriptive Data
Related Material
Special Collections and Archives also holds other transportation collections.
Index Terms
Persons:
Mertz, Lee, 1920-1993.
Corporate Names:
American Association of State Highway and Transportation Officials.; Tri-State Transportation Commission.; United States. Dept. of Transportation.; United States. Federal Highway Administration.
Subjects:
Highway planning--United States.; Transportation--United States--Planning.
Contents List
- William L. Mertz transportation collection
  - Notebook 2 - Facts About the Interstate System (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Notebook 2 Environmental Concerns Important in Building the Interstate (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Notebook 2 - History of California's Interstate Routes (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Notebook 2 - Review of the A C Rose's Writings Titled Public Roads of the Past (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Notebook 2 - Metropolitan Planning for Land Use and Transportation (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Notebook 2- Highways in the United States, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Notebook 2 - Statement on National System of Interstate and Defense Highways (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Notebook 2 - The Interstate System: Size of the Job (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Notebook 2 - Simplification of Traffic Records for Purposes of Comparison (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Notebook 2- Highways in the United States, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Notebook 1 - Correspondence Between Johnson, Pyke and MacDonald T.H. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Notebook 1- Highway Administration in the United States of North America [Address to the First Pan American Congress of Highways] October 1925 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Notebook 1- The Interstate System (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Notebook 1 - Criteria for Selection of Additional Interstate system Routes at Urban Areas June 9, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Notebook 1- Development of the Interstate Highway System August 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Notebook 1- A History of the Interstate Program - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Notebook 1 - Highway Trends and Policies [Consolidated report of Comments Made and Questions Raised at First meeting of Highway Group, Chamber of Commerce July 6,1954 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Down Tomorrow's Roads [address delivered at Texas A and M] September 7, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Notebook 1 - Federal Highway Aid Continues to Hold Congressional Support November 26, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Notebook 1 - Highway Officials Call Construction Funds Most Pressing Problem for Nations Roads November 19,1953 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Notebook 1- Research and the Engineer [ speech Delivered by Karl Moskowitz, California Highways January 7,1965 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Notebook 1 - A Touring We Will Go - American Motorist June 1928 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Notebook 1 - First national Conference on Street and Highway Safety December 15-16, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Background Leading to the Federal Aid Highway Act 1916 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Notebook 1- A History of Federal and Highway legislation (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Notebook 1 - Bureau of Public Roads (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Notebook 1 - Yearbook of the United States Department of agriculture, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Notebook 1- Federal Highway Bill Introduced by William Randolph Hearst in 1906 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Notebook 1 - To Cross America, early motorists took a long detour [article written by Drake Hokanson] (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Notebook 1 - Letter, James, Edwin W. February 21,1967 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Notebook 1 - Development of Standardized Construction Plans [ Notes from E.W. James relating to traffic signs]. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Notebook 1 - The History of Federal - Aid Highway Legislation [by Senator Carl Hayder]. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Looking Forward the Highway Future [ Paper presented at 22 Annual convention of American Association of State Highway Officials] December 7, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Notebook 1- The Interstate Highway System: Historical development [by Stromberg] (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Notebook 2 - Procedures for State highway Departments in designation of Interstate routes September 1955 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Notebook 2 - Report on he Interstate System May 30, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Notebook 2 - Some Speculations Regarding Rapid Transit [by John Brisden Walker] November 1895 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Notebook 2 - FHWA News June 1961 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Notebook 2 - Roundup of Highway News September 27, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Notebook 2 - Historical background of Federal-aid routes in Municipalities September 9,1947 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Notebook 2 - Eisenhower highway: Sequel to a Military Stunt (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Notebook 2 - Urban Transportation Planning in the United States {a good history 7 description of the urban planning process in the 60's. Proceedings of the second conference of the Australian research Board, 1964] (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Notebook 2 - A Legislative interpretation of S134 of the highway Act of 1962 February 21, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Notebook 2 - road Bureau Spurs action on urban Highway Program 12/9/63 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Notebook 2 - Interview with Francis C. Turner February 10, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Notebook 2 - Highway Needs After 1972 or What Do We Call It Now March 28, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Notebook 2 - The Highway Trust Fund [ Why it was created, Its revenues, How it operates, the arguments for and against such special funds} May 1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Notebook 2 - The Long and Costly Road [Moving Now From Building to Rebuilding] October 29, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Notebook 2 - speech on Transportation Kind-use Planning Process [F. C. Turner Speech - AASHO] December 6, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Notebook 2 - Progress of road Building in the United States (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Notebook 2 - Addendum to the Decline of the American Horse Population (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Notebook 2 - Information on Road Costs in relation to travel November 29, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Notebook 2 - Traffic To Come [ Presented at Traffic Section, national safety Congress] October 8, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Notebook 2 - Interstate Highway System has had Massive social and economic impact on nation (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Notebook 2 - Interstate highway system, now in 25th year, history's biggest public works feat (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Notebook 2 - Crozet, Claude [January 1, 1790 - January 29, 1864] (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - AASHTO Interstate Highway Research Project - Interview with Mr. W. Lee Mertz [1 of 3] March 5 and 12, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - AASHTO Interstate Highway Research Project - Interview with Mr. W. Lee Mertz [2 of 3] March 5 and 12, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - AASHTO Interstate Highway Research Project - Interview with Mr. W. Lee Mertz [3 of 3] March 5 and 12, 1998 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - AASHTO Interstate Highway Research Project - Interview with Mr. Douglas Fugate May 27 and June 10, 1987 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - The Alaska Highway [Papers of the 40h anniversary Symposium] 1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - A Personal View Tiemann, norbrt t. 1974 [ Address at annual Meeting of Southeastern association of state Highway and Transportation Officials] October 17, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Current Governmental Policies [ Joint development and Multiple use of Transportation Rights of Way ] 1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Highway Cost Allocation Study Submitted to Congress, 1965 March 25, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Along The Leesburg Pike July, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - The Little River Turnpike October, 1929 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Man in California - 1980's [by E. H. Holmes] January 28, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Solving the Rush Hour Traffic Problem [address by F.C. Turner at Annual meeting, Mississippi Valley Conference of state Highway Officials] March 15, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Moving People on Urban highways [reprint from Traffic Quarterly] July 1970 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Highway Planning [Definition by H. S Fairbank] circa 1950 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - What is This Thing Called Planning [presented at the Sixth Annual Meeting of state Highway Officials} December 8, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Transportation in the Seventies and Eighties [remarks of F. C. Turner at the Fiftieth Plenary session of the highway research Board] January 19, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Mass transportation and the Urban Highway Program April 29, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Heading in the Right Direction [address delivered at the Transportation Research Board Conference on Transportation system management] November 9, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Remarks prepared for delivery by secretary of Transportation, William T. Coleman, to American Association state Highway and Transportation Officials November 17, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Transportation: What's Ahead/ [address by federal highway administrator Norbert T. Tiemann, 49th Annual Colorado Transportation Conference] May 18, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - The Oil we Cannot Afford [Address by Norbert T. Tieman - World Highway Dinner of the International Federation] February 12, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Defusing a Timebomb [address by Norbert T. Tiemann - Annual Convention National Limestone Institute] January 29, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Federal - Aid Highway Act of 1973 August 13, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Intergovernmental roles in transportation [ remarks by Frank Herringer at the Annual Meeting of the Transportation Research Board] January 15, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Planning for the Future [address by Norbert T. Tiemann at 75th Annual Convention American Road Builders Association] February 12, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Remarks by Secretary of Transportation, Charles S. Brinegar, at the Annual Meeting of the American Association of State Highway and Transportation officials, Detroit, Michigan Nov[ember] 18, 1974 November 18, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Remarks by Federal Highway Administrator, Norbert t. Tiemann at National League of Cities 50th Anniversary Congress of Cities Albert Thomas Convention and Exhibition Center, Houston, Texas, Dec 4, 1974 December 4, 1974 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Because it is Right [Remarks by Norbert T. Tiemann at FWHA - State Highway Department s Sixth Annual Midwestern Civil rights Workshop] January 13, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - U.S. Roads and Economic Progress [by Peter G. Koltnow, President HUF presented at International Forum on the Study of Road Problems Social and economic Congress of Japan Tokyo] September 26, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Highway Transportation's response to Energy Conservation [Address by J. R. Coupal at Conference on Energy Consumption in Transportation and construction] December 3, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - [1975] a Year of Decision for Transportation [address by J. R. Coupal at 51st Annual Meeting of the Northeast association of state highway and Transportation Officials] May 7, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Transportation in 2001 [by Norbert T. Tiemann] circa February 1976 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - 1976--New Highway Perspectives for the Bicentennial year [address by J. R. Coupal at the 4th Annual Meeting of Tennesseans for Better Transportation] February 3, 1976 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Notebook 3 and 4 - Major Urban Mass Transportation Related Provisions of the Federal - Aid Highway Act of 1973 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 1976: A Year for Retrospection and Projection [Address by J. R. Coupal, Jr.,at 38th Annual Convention of Georgia Contractors' Association] February 21, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - The Future of the Highway Program [Reprint from Traffic Quarterly] January 1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Highways and the City [Address by J.C. Turner at Luncheon Meeting of the American Public works Association] August 6, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - The Federal Role in Transportation Systems of the Future [address by J. R. Coupal at the ENO Foundation for Transportation Annual Convention] October 13, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - What balanced Transportation is All About [Address by F.C. Turner at the Denver Chamber of Commerce] May 25, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Highways and Transit: A Partnership address by F.C. Turner at the 90th Annual Meeting American Transit Association] October 6, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - The Case For Buses [Remarks by F. C. Turner before the Metropolitan Section, American Society of Civil Engineers] February 9, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Balanced Transportation - - What is it? [address by F.C. Turner at National Capitol Section American Society of Civil Engineers May 20, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - To Grow With the Needs {by E.H. Holmes reprinted from Traffic Engineering] December, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Urban Transportation Planning in the U.S.: An Historical Overview [by Edward Weiner] August, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Development of the Interstate Highway System August 1964 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - William Smith Report (Excerpts) 1959 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - An Approach to the mass Transportation Problem in Washington [D.C.] December 1952 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - General T. Coleman Dupont's Delaware Highway [Souther Good Roads reprint} June 1911 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - The Delaware Highway [by Gen. T. Coleman Du Pont, Souther Good Highways reprint ] December 1911 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Wilfred Owens Harvard Dissertation [a summary] (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Iowa Road Boosters Hold Big Meeting [reprint from The Road-Maker] January 1913 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Don't Be a Piker [Putting Valuation on Fantastic Schemes for Superhighways by Ben H. Petty march 1938 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Thomas H. MacDonald Speeches(experts) 1919-1921 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - E. W. James Recollections (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - history of Public Roads Administration Participating in the war Effort November 21, 1921 - March 1946 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - The Wheeling Suspension Bridge [by Clifford M. Lewis] November 30, 1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - $400,000,000 for Highways and No Back Seat Driver (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - And Yet "Uncle" Has 34 million Dollars of Stripping Left (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Taxes Paid by Motor Vehicle Users 1933 - 1939, Disbursements of Motor Vehicles Users Taxes 1933 - 1939 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Federal - State Road Building Plan vs. Complete National Control [American Highways, by Fred R. White] January 1943 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Correspondence From and to Ralph M. Blagden April 8, 1947 and April 22, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Urban Freeways and the Interstate System [Article written by Gary T. Schwartz for Southern California law Review] 1976 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - [Report of the Department of Highway Finance] A Summary of Financial Surveys in Nine States 1936 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Problems of Financial Administration With Special Reference to Local Roads and Streets 1936 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Report of Department of Department of Highway Finance (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - The Expenditure of Motor Vehicle Revenues 1938 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - [Report of the Department of Highway Finance] Trends in highway Financial Practices 1939 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Notebook 7 - Correspondence from William T. Coleman to Douglass B. Fugate [re: rules and regulations promulgated by FHWA and UMTA under Title 23] December 31, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Letter from George Thuenen to the Editor of "County New" Notebook 7 [re:impact of transportation regulations on local agencies] November 4, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Norbert T. Tiemann to Henrik E. Stafseth Notebook 7 [re: the states comments on proposed planning regulations] March 18, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Trip to FDR Library May 12-17, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - [Columbia University] Land use Planning Studies in Relation to Local Transportation in New York City - Notebook 7 October 1, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Effect of Transportation Facilities on Future Shape of Urban Development with Emphasis on Downtown Values - Notebook 7 May 20, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Knee-deep in Decisions: Planning the Urban Decision Field [by Robert Mitchell] April 1984 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Establishing Criteria for the Design or evaluation of a Metropolitan Planning Organization [by Robert Mitchell] - Notebook 7 November - December 1981 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - the Nature of a Long range Planning Program for the Tri-State [New York Region] Committee January 12, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Federal Policy on Metropolitan Planning for Land Use and Transportation - Notebook 7 [by Robert B. Mitchell] December 20, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Planning to Solve Metropolitan Transportation Problems - Notebook 7 [ by Robert B. Mitchell, Delivered at the 5th Biennial General Assembly of the States] December 2, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - The Policy Issues in Metropolitan Transportation [by Robert B. Mitchell] - Notebook 7 September 14, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - A New York Metropolitan Regional Plan for Transportation and Land Development [Memorandum for Meeting in Albany, NY by Robert B. Mitchell] August 31, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - A City Planner Analyzes the Relationship Urban Highways and Land Development - Notebook 7 October 28, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - The Elements of a Comprehensive urban Transportation System [by Robert Mitchell] Notebook 7 October 6, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - The Innovation of the Interstate Highway System [Drawn from Dissertation of Jonathan L. Gifford] - Notebook 7 1984 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - An Analysis of the Federal Role in the Planning Design and Development of the Rural Roads,Toll Roads and Urban Freeways - Notebook 7 October 1983 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Transportation Planning - When Are Things Going to Get Better [from ITE Journal by Thomas B. Deen] August 1984 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Briefing for Meeting Between Mr. Tiemann, Mr. Herringer and Staffs - Notebook 7 May 8, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Recommendation on the Joint UMTA/FHWA Urban Regulations [memo from Mertz to Tiemann] 1975 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Accord or Discord - Notebook 7 [Address of Thos. H. MacDonald to 37th Annual Conference of American Road Builders Association] January 29, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Discussion of Hon. Thomas H. MacDonald's talk, proposed Interregional Highway System as it Affects Cities - Notebook 7 January 21, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - [Discussion of MacDonald's Talk] Proposed Interregional highway System as It Affects Cities January 21, 1944 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - The Federal-Aid Highway Program and its Relationship to Cities - Notebook 7 [address by MacDonald to Business Men's Conference on Urban Problems] September 11 - 12, 1947 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - for Better Roads [article from American Scientific June 1940 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Federal Aid Facts and Figures {article in the Constructor by Thos. B. MacDonald] April 1922 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - A Case Against Toll Roads [address by H.S. Fairbank to American Society of Civil Engineers]- Notebook 7 January 23, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - World's Fair - GM Futurama Exhibit 1939 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Planning the Interregional Highway System [H.E. Hilts] -Notebook 6 1940 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Report of the Department of Finance Thomas H. MacDonald] The Future Development of Highway Transportation [Wilfred Owen] 1941 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - the Problem of Parking Facilities - Notebook 6 1940 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - The Bragdon Committee - Notebook 8 July 16, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - The Brandon Committee Continued (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence from Jack Kinstlinger to Henrik E. Stafseth [re: hostile attitude of AASHTO]- Notebook 7 April 29, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - The Business Impact of the Super Highway- Notebook 7 1945 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Analysis of Urban Travel by Survey Technique [reprint of article from American Transit Association Conference-in-Print by Thomas H. MacDonald] - Notebook 7 1944 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Our National Highway Problems March 1921 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - The History and Development of Road Building in the United States [reprint from Transactions] - Notebook - 7 1928 (Box 6, Folder 7)